You guys see the Lamborghinis, got the Aston
Martin out, got a whole bunch of cars.
We got to figure out what this guy
did to be able to put himself here.
Are you from Los Angeles originally?
I was born in Colombia. I came
here when I was six years old.
Meet Edwin Alvareave.
Over the last 25 years, he's built one of
the largest nine-figure empires in the city of Los Angeles.
Over 25 years, how much
money has that business generated you?
That business has made over $600 million.
Despite creating a $600 million
company, Edwin didn't start here.
In fact, he spent his childhood growing up
in poverty and even living in a foster home.
Both my parents ended up in jail.
When they really put my dad away for a long time,
I made him a promise that I'd take care of the house.
And I became the head
of household at 15 years old.
And I got a chance to start
working early, and then I started hustling.
Even though at an early age, he faced extreme adversity,
he ultimately prospered and became one of the
most successful entrepreneurs in all of Los Angeles.
In this video, Edwin breaks down how he
went from being broke and living in poverty
to creating one of the most successful
nine-figure business empires in the entire world.
What's going on, everybody?
And welcome back to Questions with Multi.
Hi, millionaires.
I'm James, and I'm here with
nine-figure Los Angeles entrepreneur Edwin Arroyave.
We're going to ask him how he became successful,
how he was able to get this multimillion-dollar house.
So with that being said, let's get
started, and can't wait to figure out how.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
Home security.
I've had that now for 25 years, and I just
started a solar company a year and a half ago,
which just happens to be the
20th fastest-growing company in Inc. 5000 Magazine.
How old were you when you started your first business?
I was 21 years old.
21. And how old are you now?
I'm 46.
What's the most amount of money that your
business has ever generated in a single year?
It'll be this year. We'll do $200 million.
Scaling is one of the hardest
things to do as a business owner.
A lot of people don't have that great idea,
but they don't know how to scale and grow it.
So how have you been able
to scale to a nine-figure business?
It has to come back to influence, right?
Because to bring in good people,
they have to believe in you.
Your dream's got to be so big
that everybody's dream can fit inside of it.
Because again, good people, they have a lot of options.
But you've got to take the first step.
Faith is really taking action
before you have what you need.
Yeah, I remember.
When I started at the home security company, I
bought the minivan before I actually had the people.
Because we used to go in minivans and I used to fill
all of them up and we used to go door to door.
I didn't have a team yet, but I
bought the minivan knowing that the people were coming.
When you put money behind something,
that's when you know you're committed.
I call it a necessity level.
A necessity level is this sudden willingness that untaps this
tremendous amount of ability that you didn't know you had.
That's why I've always been great at putting
myself in pressure situations that increase my urgency level.
I believe...
Low stress is low performance.
But when you put yourself in these uncomfortable situations,
that's when that greatness that lies within comes out.
So, there's a big debate in entrepreneurship.
Whether entrepreneurs should diversify and go into a bunch
of different industries or just focus on one thing.
It seems like you've doubled down
throughout your career in the security business.
Now you're branching off a little bit into solar.
But what are your
thoughts on diversification for entrepreneurs?
Or do you think they should just
really focus on one thing throughout their career?
Well, I think in my experience
at least, you focus on one thing.
And if you're really good at it,
then that becomes your bread and butter.
And then you start to diversify, right?
But first, you have to find the business that
brings in the constant cash flow no matter what.
That way then you can invest and take some chances
in other businesses that you maybe not know as well.
But I'm a firm believer in sticking to what you
know, become really good at that, and then you could diversify.
But trying to do 10 things at the same time,
you have to get obsessed to be great at something.
For me, I wanted to be
great in the home security industry.
Like I wanted to be the best.
I want to be the best and
I'm constantly trying to improve in that.
And now we're bringing that into solar.
It took me 17 years to do
40 million in one year for security.
It took me one year to do that in solar.
But that's because I had already
paid the price for 17 years.
You've generated hundreds of millions of
dollars in revenue throughout your career.
What has been the best financial advice
that you've ever received throughout your lifetime?
Well, at the time, I didn't really have a mentor.
So I sort of just kind of
had to figure it out on my own.
But one of the great things that I did when I first started was I
would split my check three ways and I would live on a third of it.
One would go towards IRS and savings, and then the other
one would go towards a reserve account that no one could touch.
You could call me and ask me for money.
To me, that reserve account did not exist.
And that reserve account has always helped me through
tough times because in life, life and pain are inseparable.
And you're going to have
to go through some tough times.
So for me, because I like nice things, but being
able to cut it three ways allowed me not to
live
outside my means.
That said, I was huge on having nice things.
It's what made me want to work hard.
I wanted to stand out.
I wanted to be rare.
You know, at 21 years old, I wanted to be the
first 21 year old in my city driving a Mercedes convertible.
I didn't want to do it when I
was 28 because by then everybody had a Mercedes.
Right.
So just little ways that I would compete against myself.
What is the greatest dream that
you've ever accomplished throughout your lifetime?
It has to be my first one.
I promised my mom that I
would buy her a dream house.
And at 21 years old, I remember being woken up
by a roach and I said, this is
the last time a roach wakes me up.
And I went to an open house that
weekend and I realized that, wait a minute,
all I have to do is come up
with twelve thousand dollars as a down payment.
All I got to do is come
up with fourteen hundred dollars a month.
And I'm like, I do that in one day.
So I grabbed my mom, picked
her up, took her to the house.
I said, Mom, this home
will be yours in 90 days.
And at that point, I sort of tricked myself
into success because I wasn't going to let her down.
She started crying. I started crying.
And then I just knew, like I
said earlier, with regards to the blueprint, I
knew I needed to do eight
to ten sales for twelve weeks straight.
And if I did that, I would
be able to buy my mom her house.
And that's the reason I did not
quit when it was eight o'clock, nine o'clock.
And I wanted to stop
because I didn't have a result.
I was like, I'm not leaving
here until I get a deal.
And then I can't tell you how many deals
I got at 930, 10 o'clock at 910 30.
And then I started filling myself up with belief.
And I think the reason people don't
buy from you is because you look desperate.
I didn't look desperate anymore because I
knew that somehow, some way I would always
get to sell at the end of the day.
But it started.
It was my mom's dream.
And if you don't come from a rich
family, a rich family can come from you.
And I made the decision in my family that
I was going to be the one person that
changed my family tree forever.
This video is sponsored by BetterHelp.
A lot of the time mentors will tell you
that getting in shape and getting
in the gym is crucial for self-improvement.
I'm here to tell you that
your mental health is just as important.
A lot of the times
as entrepreneurs, we're faced with roadblocks,
limiting beliefs, loneliness while building our businesses.
BetterHelp connects you with a licensed
therapist who is trained to listen
and give you helpful and unbiased advice.
As entrepreneurs, we have limited time
in our schedule, but through BetterHelp,
you have the opportunity to have therapy
sessions through phone call, video chat or
even messaging, whatever the most comfortable
version of therapy is for you.
BetterHelp can match you to one of over
30,000 therapists in their network, which may
give you access to a wider range
of expertise than what may be available in your area.
To get started, you'll fill out
a questionnaire to help assess your specific
needs, and then you'll be matched with
a therapist in most cases within 48 hours.
When starting therapy, you can easily switch
to a new therapist at no additional cost
without stressing about insurance, who's in
your network or anything like that.
On the journey to self-improvement, we're always
trying to constantly better ourselves and we spend
hours in the gym. But why
not give our mind that same attention?
If you think you might
benefit from therapy, consider BetterHelp.
Click the link in the description below or go
to BetterHelp.com to get 10% off your first month.
Now, with that being said,
let's get back to the video.
When it comes to the way that
people look at money in today's world,
what would you say is the biggest thing
that separates the middle class from the wealthy?
At least for me, again, in my
experience, you've got to have a good relationship.
I think a lot of people
have a bad relationship with money.
If you're always worried about not having enough
money, if you're always worried about not saving
enough money, then what happens is you
start to hoard all of your money.
And what happens when you hoard all of your
money, you never go out and touch the dream,
taste the dream. And if you never
touch the dream or go taste the dream,
then you're not going to want to get
off your ass to go make it happen.
So, what happens then is then you
become complacent, hoping that one day you'll
have enough savings to finally take action
to have whatever it is that you want.
But the reality of it,
unfortunately, is the chances of that
happening are slim to none. What probably will happen
is you're going to get punched in the face,
you're going to get knocked down. And at that
point, it's going to take most of your money,
if not all of your money. And then you're
stuck in this endless vicious cycle of trying to have
enough money so you could finally take action and
become whatever it is that you want to become.
But in reality, you should become first, then
take action, and then you could have whatever
it is that you want. And that's an
abundance mindset for me. I started with becoming. Becoming
is like we said earlier, you have to have
hope, the desire to want to do something great.
Faith, knowing that it's going to happen,
taking action before you have what you need.
And then you have to believe in
yourself. And believing in yourself means believing something
in your heart before you actually have
it. Believing that you're worth a million dollars
a year in your heart before you actually have it.
The only way that ever happens is if you step into
the uncertainty of something that demands more than
you think you're worth. And when you do,
when you succeed at it, then what happens is
you start taking action before you have what you need,
because you realize you're a money-making machine.
And the money's already in its way. The
other thing that happens when you take action before
you have what you need is it sends a signal
to God, causes him to act, and now the right people
start showing up. The other thing that happens is
you get a blueprint on what you need to make
that happen now. And all you have to do is
break it down to the ridiculous. The more you can break
it down to the ridiculous, the more
attainable it becomes. The more attainable it becomes,
the more realistic it becomes, the more you're going
to want to get off your butt. Because what
causes you to take action is your ability
to think you can get a result. Wow.
And then you get have, which is when you put a
date on when you're going to do it by. And then
you go all out. Because if you don't put a date
on when you're going to do it by, then it just becomes
a dream and you procrastinate. I've always been on about
dates. I'm going to do it 90 days later. And
then you go after it like your life depends on
it. And the hardest part about this little formula I'm
giving you is that for whatever reason, right as
you're going to get your blessing, you're going to
get your biggest test. You're going to get punched.
You're going to get knocked down. And it's at that
point where you got to make a decision. Do you
spring back up and revert back to who you used
to be? Someone that makes excuses on you? Or do you
just go back to who you used to be? And then you
all the time? Or do you continue to push
forward having faith that the right people are going to
show up and you focus on what you can control
and then everything happens at the end? I can't tell
you how many times miracles have happened just because
I did not quit. I was like, I don't know
how we're going to do this but we're going to
make this happen and the right people have shown out.
And I call that my abundance formula. I've used
that to attain everything I have in my life. I
could sit here for hours and tell you
stories on incredible things that have happened just using
that formula.
You talked about taking action. For someone who's
stuck in their nine to five right now and
they're miserable in their day-to-day life, what advice
would you give them to really create the
absolute best life for themselves?
So it's figuring out the why. Too many people
are worried about the what, the how, the where,
the when. Not enough people are worried about the
why. The why is the one thing you have to
be certain about. And then once you find that out,
again, you break it down to if it's a dream,
how much money do you need to be making
a year, right? For me to make six, seven,
eight figures a year, you don't have
to be that smart. You just need a
little bit of time to figure out what you need
to be making a year. And then you can find an
opportunity that allows you to make that kind of
money. And number two is you need to find someone
who's got a vested interest in your success that's
going to help you do it. And that's the hardest
one. But if you find that, then the only reason
you wouldn't make it is because you don't work hard.
But that's what I would do is I'd find something
that will allow you to make the kind of money you
want to make so that you can live out your
dream, whatever that is. And then I find someone that
has been successful at it, that has a vested
interest in your success that's going to help you
do it.
As an entrepreneur, for someone who may not have
that belief in God or that faith in their life,
what advice would you give to them?
That whether you like it or not,
you're faith-based. Faith is just the projection
of the most beautiful possible thing for
the future. The opposite of faith is fear,
which is the worst possible thing for the future.
If you think about it, they both haven't happened
yet. You just have to choose, are you going
to be positive or are you going to be negative?
90% of winning in life is just being
positive. And that's where faith is so important.
For someone who's
trying to find that relationship, what advice would
you give to people that are really trying
to build their relationship with God?
Give yourself grace. We're not perfect. It's
why we need God. If we were perfect,
we wouldn't need him. So you're going to fall
and you're going to make mistakes. But what I would
say the adversary wants you to do is when you
make those mistakes is he tries to pull you away and
say, hey, if you go back, you're a hypocrite,
but that's where he wants you. And it's when you're
going through those struggles that you should have
a connection with God. And it doesn't happen
overnight. For me, I wrestled with it for 18
years, 20 years, but it was a long time.
It was in my heart that I knew that I
needed to get closer to God because it didn't matter how
much success I got. I always felt a little
empty. There was always something empty in my heart.
Every dream I've accomplished. And it was just, I'm
like, all right, I got to go to something else.
And it's been, it's been a game changer for me.
And it's not a bad thing, but I used to think
that exterior factors like women, exotic
cars, big houses would give me happiness.
And just through my ups and downs, I've
realized that those things didn't bring me happiness.
They brought me pleasure. Now there's nothing wrong
with pleasure, but just keep in mind that
pleasure is a sensation and therefore it's unstable
because in the scales of life, it's always going
to get balanced out by the discomfort and pain that
you have to go through. So one of the ways
that I've realized that my happiness comes from
is living inside out versus exterior in. And the
way you live inside out, which has been the
biggest game changer for me is gratitude exercises. And
then number two is being able to take a negative
and turn it into a positive. You could do those
two things. You start to live inside out
versus exterior in. You have a multimillion dollar house
out here in Los Angeles, California. But for
someone who's aspiring to live this type of
lifestyle someday, what is your best advice to
the younger generation out there? If there's one
message that you would pass on to the
younger generation, what would that be? So I think,
you know, my life is, I've had to
reverse engineer my life because for many years,
up until six years ago, I can tell you how
I succeeded. I just knew that I worked hard. I
had discipline. I had perseverance. I had a lot of success.
I had a lot of success. I had a lot of
perseverance. I had integrity and I had big
faith. But other than that, I couldn't really
tell you how I succeeded. Now that I've
been studying mindset, I've came across this thing
called the reticular activating system. And
you could actually Google this stuff. So,
the reticular activating system is part of your
subconscious mind. And what you got to understand
about your subconscious mind is that
it sees everything and it hears everything,
but it intentionally does not share it back
to your conscious mind. Because if it did,
your mind would get overwhelmed and you would
go to sleep. So instead, your subconscious mind,
filters what information it's going to send to your
conscious mind. And it does it by the way
of the reticular activating system. And the only thing
it allows to get to your conscious mind is
anything having to do with your dreams, which
is why you're supposed to have some big God-sized
dreams. Anything having to do with your self-worth, which
is why you got to build your identity. And
anything that has to do with your survival, which
is why you got to get obsessed with the things
that you want. Because sometimes if you don't
do those three things, you could have an opportunity
that would change your life forever. And you won't
be able to do that. And that's why you're supposed
to have a dream. And you won't even see it. As
I look back to the decision I made at 21 years old,
when I left the job that was paying me $70,000
a year and everybody thought I was crazy. I could
tie it back to that. Because at 12 years old, I
used to daydream all day long on how one day I was
going to make a hundred grand by the age of
21. I started going to Bordeaux Drive in Beverly Hills
and I started dreaming of how one day I was going
to end up there. I had these huge dreams. I had
my self-worth, which was already kind of high
because I had accomplished some good things at
a young age and I needed it for survival. Like I
was like, I'm going to make it. I'm going to make
it. Like there was no way that I wasn't going to
succeed. I made a promise to my mom. I made a
promise to my dad and I was going to
make it happen. So the understanding that is huge.
Guys, that's a wrap on today's video. Be sure
to leave a like and subscribe for some amazing
content coming soon. And everybody click right here
to watch us going all around Miami, Florida,
asking multimillionaires how you can
become successful in today's world.